Thank you.
I've always been good at embodying my characters.
Some say it's a gift.
Yes, it's been my dream since I was a girl.
Oh, well...
You know you can no longer continue living this way.
Come with me into the spotlight.
Actors, designers, performers, filmmakers.
Time to take the stage.
Come on, let's go.
I get your prize, honey.
I'll take it to your latter dreams.
Theaters, look at that marquee.
And parties full of celebrities.
Painting, pounding, paparazzi, too.
Till the day your name is on the walk of fame.
Don't stop now, dream big.
But beware, don't forget.
If your restless feet should trip and fall.
There's no turning back from your calling.
You know it's true.
What may look from afar like diamonds
are actually a poor romantic's tears.
But don't give up and don't give in.
You have to keep that dream alive.
Dance on fire.
Time to heat things up now.
Go on with your song and dance.
You may be burnt out.
But your dreams, they keep on blazing.
Beating on and on.
And so slow for your close-up.
And roll, roll.
Great!
Cut!
Next shot!
That's it for the wide!
Prep for the next shot!
Let's move those cranes!
Great job.
As always, Miss Dia.
Oh, that's so sweet of you, Gene.
Now, see, it'll be more dramatic.
Come from the side?
Push it.
I'll move the camera, then.
Thanks.
Sure.
Hey, what you writing in there, huh?
Well, there are so many things to learn about on a film set.
That's why I'm taking notes on everything.
Wow.
You must really like studying.
What?
No, I...
Have no fear!
I am here!
Tis I!
Pumple!
How is everyone?
Hi!
Hi, Pumple.
You're looking sexier than ever, Miss Dia.
So, how's it going, Mr. Director?
Why don't you take a look for yourself?
Oh, yes, yes.
The perfect blend of fear and sex appeal.
I know, right?
Oh, hey, Pumple, are we all set for that meeting?
I've been Pumple's assistant for about a year now, watching and learning from the sidelines.
Gene!
Huh?
Grab us some sandwiches.
Uh, yes, right away.
Tuna, please!
Got it!
Pumple's an amazing producer, but for some reason, she only works on B-movies.
Um...
I was just wondering, do you only like B-movies or something?
No, I like all movies.
Pompo's not really all that picky.
Oh.
But this is going to be a summer release,
so it's got to have sun, the sea, and a little skin.
A good excuse to show off Mistia's body.
You know, there's a direct correlation between your lead actresses' looks
and how good the movie will be.
Really? Is that true?
With the right lead, Pompo can transform any screenplay into a good movie.
The truth is, making the audience cry is actually pretty easy.
Making them fall in love with something vapid takes a stroke of genius.
Oh, I guess that makes a lot of sense.
Hey, what's on the schedule for tomorrow?
Auditions for the movie that Corbett is directing.
Oh, cool. We'll be deciding the fate of young people.
You better not be late then, Gene.
Uh, good night.
Oh, my God.
A perfect shot.
Peter's in, Peter's in film.
Sorry.
You're late!
What did I tell you last night, huh?
Your auditions are already over.
I'm so sorry.
Now make yourself useful and get me a treat.
And it better have chocolate in it!
Yes, ma'am.
Right away, ma'am.
That girl.
Was she the last one to audition?
She was.
And it's such a shame that the kid can't act.
Well, I'll be in the screening room if you need me.
Oh.
Yes!
Ah.
Oh.
Oh-oh.
Oh!
Oh.
Whoa.
Fire it up! Who's in the mood for a seafood boy?
This is incredible. It's so trashy, it's still a great movie.
Pumpo can take any script and make it into a hit.
She truly is a genius.
That brain shot really paid off.
That part was so awesome. I was like, oh no, they didn't.
Grandpa!
Hmm?
You made it!
Who knew that a movie with that many cute behinds could be so entertaining?
I know, right?
There he is, a titan in the film world.
Legendary producer J.D. Peterson.
I've seen so many of his movies that have lost count.
After he retired from the industry, his granddaughter, a young cinephile, inherited all of his connections.
But that's not all she inherited.
His eye for spotting great scripts, actors, directors, his charisma, his decisiveness.
Everything needed to produce great movies, making her a silver screen prodigy.
Hey, Pumpo! They want us to take some PR shots!
Okay! Catch up with you later!
Um, Mr. Peterson?
Hmm?
Oh, you're Stan, the Unsinkable Battleship Handsome.
It's Gene.
Uh, I wanted to know the secret to making a great movie.
Hmm? Hmm.
There's no real correct way to make a movie.
Oh, yeah, right.
But a film set is a living thing.
From the actors' moods to the changing scenes, you need to have a sharp eye.
That way, you'll never miss a moment that sparkles.
I need to have a sharp eye. Got it.
And I'm guessing you're asking because you hope to make your own movie one day?
What? No! No way! I could never! Not in my wildest dreams!
There, there. You've gotta relax, son.
There's a reason Pumpo chose you to be on her team.
Huh? Uh, she what?
Look, a producer's job is basically all about spotting talent.
Have you considered that the reason Pumpo keeps you around
is because she sees something in you? Hmm?
Wait. You mean... really?
Hmm.
I think you're right. It would make a good adaptation.
Hey, Mr. Director.
Hmm?
A word?
It's decided.
That is correct, Gene, my boy.
You will be cutting the trailer for Marine.
Wh- Whaaaaat?
But, but, but, but doesn't a producer usually hire a special trailer house
to do something like that?
You wanna make movies, right?
Well, you gotta take risks and not do what everyone else usually does.
Hmm. Hmm. Hmm. Hmm.
I'm gonna need you to cut a 15-second spot.
You know how to use editing software, right?
Well, yes, but...
Grab their attention right from the top.
Give them a taste of some of the best parts,
but mislead them to create buzz.
And then...
End of the thing!
Something like that.
All that in just 15 seconds?
Yup.
The 15-second trailer teaser is the spot that most people will see,
which means it also directly affects the box office.
The livelihoods of the entire crew and their families
lie solely in your hands now. Got it?
It is simply impossible to realistically fit all of that into just 15 seconds.
That's not enough time.
That's why I'm going to include outside footage.
One technique of filmmaking
is to make the audience imagine the next scene without showing it.
They don't have to show everything.
I'll let the audience fill in the gaps in their heads.
I'm not even thinking about box office or the crew's livelihoods right now.
Because I'm having too much fun!
It was supposed to be another typical vacation.
Well, so what do you think?
Mr. Director?
Hmm...
That's Pompo, isn't it?
Yes, that's right.
Oh!
Yeah, I remember waving to Mistia right after we rapped.
Why would you include that shot?
Uh...
Well...
I wanted to mislead the audience to create some buzz.
And I happened to find that footage.
I messed up, didn't I?
Hmm...
It's great!
Uh...
I love it!
Huh?
So Gene can make the 30-second, two-minute, and online versions, right?
Works for me!
Thank you so much!
I saw you.
You were talking to my grandpa yesterday.
You know, I didn't expect that.
Yeah, that's right.
You said something I wanted to ask you about.
Hmm?
I was wondering why you decided to make me your assistant.
There are so many others.
People who have better schooling, better looking,
are just all around better than me.
So then, what made you choose me?
Ah, that's an easy one.
Huh?
People possess one quality that nobody else has.
Your eyes.
Don't sparkle!
Huh?
If you take a look into everyone else's eyes,
they sparkle brilliantly with the hope of adolescent optimism.
But the truth is, a fulfilling life gives you a perspective
that lacks a certain depth.
And so happiness destroys creativity.
So those others aren't qualified to be creators.
However, when I looked into your eyes,
I saw the typical signs of an outcast with nothing going for him.
That's a compliment.
Uh, thank you?
People who don't fit in the real world
create their own world inside of their mind.
The expanse and depth of an outcast's inner world
is directly correlated to their untapped creative potential.
And that's why I put my faith in a complete loner.
Like you.
Because it's all in the eyes.
Oh, I see.
Oh, no, it's happening again.
Like the other day?
I feel like I'm forgetting something.
About the screening?
Or about the audition yesterday?
That's it?
Pompa remembers what it is.
A little light bulb went on.
I didn't notice at the time.
Here it is.
Arrange a meeting with her.
Uh, yes, ma'am.
Uh, this girl.
Does she have the eyes of an outcast, too?
No!
Because an actress needs sparkling eyes!
I can't put my finger on it yet.
But there's just something about her.
No matter.
Because when it comes to making movies,
sometimes you just gotta go with your gut.
Right?
Um, would it be okay if I use the screening room?
Sure!
Whatcha gonna watch?
Just, uh, cinema paradiso.
Ugh, I hate that one.
What?
But that movie's a masterpiece.
Eh, it's a good story, but it's way too long.
So, you don't like long movies?
Ugh, I hate them.
But don't you think the longer they are, the longer you have to enjoy them?
You got it all wrong.
Let me tell you a story.
When I was a kid, my parents were always busy.
So, my grandpa raised me.
And the only thing my grandpa knows are movies.
So he made me watch them.
Do you know how tough it is for a little kid to sit still for two to three hours?
He would force me to watch the entire thing and then make me tell him what I thought.
So a simple story told in 90 minutes or less was like an oasis in a desert of celluloid.
And that is one of the reasons why I can't stand long movies.
What are the others?
Making people concentrate for two hours or sometimes more is simply unkind to modern audiences.
Filmmakers should recognize that every shot is precious and attempt to convey their vision as concisely as possible.
I mean, a bloated film isn't beautiful.
It's just indulgent, yeah?
But I love watching movies so much that I don't mind sitting for three or even four hours if...
Ah! This is what's wrong with you film buffs!
Being able to pick the brain of one of the industry's greats from such a young age...
I envy her.
Mind if I join you?
Huh?
Miss Pompoh!
Did you want to watch the movie as well?
It's already halfway over though.
Great!
Cause I didn't want to watch the whole thing.
If it's a masterpiece, then checking it out is only apropos.
Ugh.
Huh?
I'm getting deja vu.
I wonder why...
Good morning, Miss Pompoh!
Huh?
I guess she hasn't come in yet.
Meister, is this what Pompo's been working on?
Pompo has returned for breakfast!
Probably shouldn't have eaten so much,
because this is one stuffed tummy.
Okay, noted.
How do you like the script?
Oh, well, I...
I agree. It's so true.
Pompo is simply incapable of writing a boring script.
I want you to give me a detailed analysis right now.
Yes, I... I can do that.
An aging artist finds peace
when he travels to the countryside and meets a young girl.
This story's a bit of a cliché.
But that said,
these characters are completely unique and compelling.
Delbert, the arrogant and talented conductor
yet naive about the world.
Lily, who at times acts like an inquisitive boy
and at others, like a sensitive girl.
These are the two main characters alone.
But they manage to carry the entire film!
It's incredible how a B-movie producer such as yourself
managed to write such a perfectly crafted, poignant story.
Ah, I see, I see.
So you think I'm nothing more than a B-movie producer?!
I'm so sorry!
But, uh, it's not just the story.
You go from the bustle of the city,
then to the sweeping, majestic views of the Alps.
It's so liberating.
If I saw that on the big screen,
it would take my breath away.
One more question for you, Gene.
Out of all the scenes,
which one did you like the best?
Uh, easy.
It's the one where Lily is singing
and then looks over her shoulder.
Oh, that was a quick answer.
Well, it's the moment when Delbert
finally regains his passion for music.
And also, when I read it,
man, I could picture it immediately.
Hmm.
You have passed.
However, looking through it,
most of these scenes
only have two actors in them,
which means you're going to have to cast
really strong actors.
It's already cast.
We offered Delbert to Martin Braddock,
and he's accepted.
What?
M-Martin Braddock?
But he's a legend.
The best actor ever.
Uh, wait.
Didn't he retire?
He no longer felt inspired,
so he got more picky
and hasn't said yes to anything
for ten years.
That is, until I got Grandpa
to convince him.
Wow.
Martin Braddock's first film
in ten years.
That'll make for great PR.
This movie's gonna be a hit now
for sure.
And for Lily we're casting.
Um,
excuse me?
Yes.
Right on cue.
I got my hair cut
just like you asked me to.
How is it?
Oh, nice.
It really suits you, Natalie.
It's...
It's Lily.
I'm staring right at Lily.
I know.
She's perfect
because I wrote it for her.
That's why...
Oh.
The first time I set eyes on her,
I caught a glimmer of it.
A scene awash
with a brilliant, beautiful light.
And so,
in order to try to capture
that brief flash of light,
I wrote this script.
So then sometimes,
scripts are written
for specific actors?
Occasionally,
an entire story
will unfold in your mind
when you meet
that special someone.
Generally speaking,
that means you have
a fantastic movie
on your hands.
I see.
Um, excuse me,
but can you explain to me
what you two are talking about?
I shall enlighten.
Congratulations on being cast
in your first movie.
Huh?
Ah!
Wait!
All of a sudden?
How did this happen?
Here you go.
I don't believe it!
I am going to let you
shoot this screenplay of mine.
Best of luck.
Director Jean.
I apologize,
but we're doing
some construction up ahead.
Understood.
This way!
Sorry for the inconvenience!
Excuse me!
Whoa!
No, no, no,
I can't sleep.
I have to take a shower
and go to that audition.
Oh, no!
I'm late.
Oh!
Hmm.
Number 15!
My name's Natalie Woodward.
I'm here to audition.
No!
Too plain!
That's my 30th rejection.
No wonder I'm so depressed.
You're late!
The auditions are already over!
I-I am so sorry.
Too expensive.
Hmm.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
My smile is my best asset,
and I am never going to give up!
I will not abandon my dreams.
It's the reason I came to this town!
I'm here! I got here as soon as I could!
Sorry to make you rush over.
Uh, Natalie Woodward.
Born in Sun Road, a town known for its corn, zero acting experience.
What are you currently doing to make money?
Oh, well, I have a part-time job.
How many days a week?
Every day, I'm afraid.
And are you in acting classes?
I can only afford once every two weeks.
Come on, how do you expect to become a movie star at that rate?
I assume you're familiar with the lovely Mistia.
Of course! I wish I could be half as beautiful as she is.
You're going to quit your day job.
You'll also move out of your apartment and in with Mistia.
From now on, you'll be her apprentice.
You will shadow her every day.
I'll call her later and give her a heads up.
You will receive the same exact training as her.
And you will learn by observing her on set.
Understood?
Huh? Yes.
Then why are you still standing here?
Go!
Hello. You must be Natalie. Nice to meet you.
Hi. It really is her.
She's even more beautiful in person.
This place is huge.
I was just about to head over to the gym.
Would you like to come along with me?
Yes!
You have amazing abs.
Yeah.
I typically lay off the workouts when I'm filming.
Turns out boys aren't that into muscles.
Oh!
That was my first time working out.
My whole body hurts.
Leave the cooking to me.
It's the least I can do for you.
And I know how to make plenty of healthy dishes to keep your camera ready.
So Natalie, I heard that you wanted to be an actress ever since you were a little girl.
Yes, that's right.
Well then, I hope you book something real soon.
Yeah!
Even the smallest star in the sky shines like an angel from the heavens!
No, no, no. Do you even know what you're saying? You sound like you're reading.
Right! I'm so sorry.
Here. You thirsty?
Yes, thank you so much.
Oh no! Puffo has arrived!
So, how's it going?
Natalie.
Show me your face.
Oh!
What is she doing?
Very good.
She's almost ready.
Huh?
Yes, got it.
Oh, a haircut.
All right, I will let her know.
Don't you worry, okay?
You're finally making a move at last, huh, Pumbo?
Oh, Natalie, Miss Pumbo would like to see you at the studio tomorrow. Also, I got my hair cut just like you asked me to.
I got my hair cut just like you asked me to.
Director Jean!
What? Director?
Oh, wait. That's me.
I can't believe this is happening to us.
I feel so giddy that I'm trying not to faint.
Yeah, me too.
I'm so nauseous.
Hey there.
Mistia!
You know, whether you two are ready or not, this movie is going to get made.
This is your chance to fulfill your lifelong dreams.
Don't just stand there. Go out there and network.
Here I go!
Okay, Jean. It's your turn now.
You're Jean, the director, am I right?
It's Martin!
Best of luck.
Right?
Thanks for doing this.
Ah, there you are.
I don't believe my eyes.
Two legends who between them have won six Nia Academy Awards are standing right before me.
Good. Good to see you again, sir.
Hmm?
Wait a minute.
You're a hawk and animal of the road warriors.
I'm Jean.
We've met.
Yes, of course.
It's Jean, right?
Congratulations, director.
Thank you so much, sir.
For a big star, Martin gets lonely easily, so no need to give him space.
Try to engage with him as much as possible.
Oh, right.
Jean!
Uh, director Corbett.
Your first movie.
Congratulations.
Thanks, and congratulations to you on the success of Marine.
No, no.
My crew deserves all the credit.
Hey, Jean, would you mind if I give you one piece of advice?
Yes, of course you may.
Since this is your first film and Martin is your star, it means you're going to be under
a whole lot of pressure.
If you try to please everyone, your movie's going to be a directionless mess.
But here's how to fix that.
All you have to do is think about the one person you want to show the movie to the most.
And as long as you make it for them, your movie will end up with a laser-sharp focus.
That makes sense.
I've been pretty worried about screwing it all up, so that was helpful.
What?
She's the female lead, not you?
Yeah, I'm actually not even in it.
I'm going to be playing the female lead!
Oh, man.
What a disappointment.
Anyway, the name's Martin Braddock, the best actor in the world.
Shall we exchange socials?
I don't have a smartphone, sorry.
Oh, Martin was so disappointed that I'm the lead.
Could that mean I'm not good enough?
Oh, Director Jean!
I get heartburn when I hear that.
Can I ask you something?
Yes?
Is it weird to have me playing your female lead?
Maybe I'm not attractive enough.
I'm so nervous about this that part of me wants to run away.
But when I think about it, I'd just be running away from reality.
And where would I run to, since this is the only place I belong?
So I only have two choices.
Make the movie, or die.
And so, I'm doing this no matter what.
I won't run.
I won't!
Blue skies.
Cornfields as far as the eye can see.
That's all there is in my hometown.
And that's the reason I loved movies so much.
They were a way for me to escape.
A way for me to dream.
One day, I'm going to become an actress!
Don't worry, my dear.
You'll make a wonderful actress one day, Natalie.
Ever since that day, I worked as hard as I could.
I saved up all my money so that I could come here to N'yallywood.
This is my big break.
It's also my whole life.
Ah, you know...
Yes?
I just remembered something Pompo said to me.
She said as long as your lead actress is attractive,
you've nothing to worry about.
Because your movie will be a hit.
You were hand-picked by Pompo herself.
So you're attractive because you're attractive enough to be a lead actress.
You know?
And regardless, I can't see anyone else in the role of Lily.
You don't need to worry.
Just let me take care of the rest.
Mm, all right.
Thank you for the confidence.
Let's make a movie, director!
Huh?
Yes?
What?
You're not sleeping?
Oh, well, I'm just going over some notes from the location manager.
Make sure to get plenty of rest.
Don't forget, that's also part of your job.
Sorry, I need to go to the restroom.
You just went, Alan.
Now you look here.
This is a huge contract for us.
Don't mess it up.
Got that?
I won't.
We'll see.
I know him.
But how?
Hello!
Bumbo has arrived in Switzerland!
Oh, this is great.
The despondent Dalbert lands in Switzerland and is moved to tears by the splendor of the Alps.
That is such a great idea.
I know, right?
No, it won't work.
What?
When he first arrives here, his heart is closed off to the outside world.
He's not even capable of noticing the scenery.
Oh.
Ah!
Sorry!
I have no right to challenge any of your creative ideas!
Nah, it's fine.
You're the director, after all.
Uh, yes, sir.
It takes a village to make one of these little movies.
Just know that I will never hesitate to give you my opinion.
And it's your job to take it or leave it.
Uh, right.
Everyone, feel free to give your creative input.
Okay!
There are benefits to having veteran actors in your cast.
Look how far I've come, Grandma.
And Mistia, I'll do my best.
Scene 32, shot one, take one.
Exterior, meadow, Alps.
We see the heartbroken Delbert.
He meets Lily for the first time.
Ready?
Got it.
Rolling!
Action!
This is the power of the best actor in the world.
He's usually so lively, but as soon as the cameras rolled, he embodied despondency.
However, what's even more surprising, though, is Lily.
Her star quality is undeniable.
She's perfect, because I wrote it for her.
This is what it looks like when a script is written for an actor.
So, Martin, will you be going back to Nellywood to shoot the orchestra scene after we're done filming here?
That's the plan.
How?
Do you have to go through conductor training or anything?
Actually, it's not a problem.
Martin has played a conductor twice previously.
In the climax of the film, Walter, he had to conduct a live, full orchestra.
The scene was a single shot lasting six minutes and 40 seconds.
And it made cinematic history.
Professional musicians praised his performance, saying it was perfect.
So, I'm sure he'll remember how to do it with very little coaching.
Uh.
Sorry, did I say something wrong?
Oh, I'm speechless.
That's Jean for you.
You really are amazing.
You know everything there is about movies.
Well, it's all I have.
Honestly, I'm happy and shocked that you're familiar with one of my older films.
Well, of course I am.
I've seen every one of your films.
They're all masterpieces.
I like you.
Let's call it a day and drink until dawn.
Oh, there we are.
So, let's frame it with the sun on the right.
But I also want the shot to be a little backlit.
You got that?
The director's really particular about the lighting.
He's done so many setups.
It's the scene where you take Delbert for a walk with all the goats.
My guess is he just wants to do the whole thing in a single take.
Oh.
Hmm?
Huh?
I'm so sorry about this.
The roof fell in and spooked them.
We patched it up as best we could, but...
It was pretty rickety to start with.
But I thought there were supposed to be more goats.
Well, you see...
They were eaten by wolves?
Great things!
That means we don't have enough goats.
What do we do now?
What did the goat herder say?
It's impossible to get more.
Should we postpone then?
Except we have a limited number of shooting days at this location.
And the weather's about to change.
The fog's rolling in.
Fog, huh?
Do we have a smoke machine handy?
But why?
It's okay. Don't be afraid.
Come. This way.
The smoke was a great idea.
And the goats were the right amount of scary.
There also ended up being enough of them with the cutouts we made.
The script merely described Delbear and Lily going for a walk.
Way to go, Gene!
Well, today's a wash.
You want to try to shoot all the interiors instead?
Gene? Gene, hey!
What do you say?
Uh, could I shoot an additional scene that's not in the script?
You're a funny guy. You don't gotta ask me. You're the boss after all.
Why do I have to do this?
This is the neat thing.
More working and less smoking.
And hurry it up before one of the goats catches a cold.
Got it. I got it.
Yeah, that works.
It's a great scene.
I also want a shot of the rain clearing.
I hope we get a rainbow.
Director?
Uh, yes?
I was going to try falling off the roof.
What do you think?
I just like the idea of Delbear getting more humiliated.
I love it!
And we can even have Lily point and laugh at him.
Then Delbear gets so angry that he loses it and throws mud at Lily!
Huh?
I'm sorry.
I got carried away.
No, it's a great idea.
I didn't expect it at all.
Oh, when he falls, I think he should land in front of the door.
And then we could have a goat come out and lick his face.
In that case...
Oh.
You're stuck up, windbag!
Hey, look, Gene!
Quick, shoot it!
Great, and cut!
Man, the weather was on our side after all.
That's gonna be one killer scene.
Uh, thank you.
I appreciate it.
Scene 42 is up.
Montage, Dal Bear and Lily.
Scene 44, Dal Bear learns how to fish.
Oh, hold on.
That song!
Pumple!
Yes!
This is the scene that makes the whole movie!
I'm completely satisfied.
All right, I'll see you back in Yollywood.
You're not staying to supervise the rest of the shoot?
I'm still working on finding you a full orchestra.
And let me tell you, it's gonna be a scheduling nightmare.
Oh, and Gene, my boy?
Yeah, what?
This movie is gonna bring home in the Academy Award, I'm sure of it.
Uh-huh.
Later!
I leave it to you, Director.
Huh?
Stand by, please!
It's him.
The guy from the plane.
Oh, thank you.
I think I know you.
You're Jean, right?
You're always writing in that book.
About what?
Just my thoughts on movies.
Oh.
Here you go.
Maybe you should try looking at where you're going next time.
That way you won't drop or lose something important.
Man, it took so long.
My bad.
Jean!
Jean Feeney!
Huh?
I thought I knew you from somewhere.
It's Alan.
We went to high school together.
A movie director?
That's amazing.
I can hardly believe in myself either.
I still feel bad about your notebook.
That's okay.
I'd actually memorized it, so I just rewrote it in a new one.
So, what do you do, Alan?
Oh.
Yallywood Bank.
Oh, wow.
That's major.
No, it sucks.
I hate it.
I...
Again, I apologize.
I had no idea that he hated golf, sir.
Sorry doesn't fix things.
If you were on the ball, you would have researched the client.
It's basic.
I expect more from an intern.
You may have been a hotshot analyst, but you're an associate now.
You can't coast on by anymore.
You have to do real work.
I'm sorry, sir.
Lately, I've even been considering quitting.
But why?
I've never had any real ambitions or goals.
Everything just came naturally to me.
But real life is nothing like high school.
It's harsher.
And everything slips into nothingness.
Oh, sorry.
Uh, hello?
Understood.
I, uh, gotta run.
Uh, let me know when your movie comes out, and I'll go see it.
And, um, thanks for the chat.
Yeah, likewise.
You know what, Gene?
I take it back.
I was wrong.
You were looking ahead all along.
I can see the sparkle in your eyes now.
Huh?
Is it true?
My eyes sparkle?
Nice!
And cut!
We did it!
That's a wrap!
We got it!
Yeah!
Woo-hoo!
Now!
Time to celebrate!
Oh, Grandma!
You were right!
I did it!
Huh?
Mr. Director!
Thank you so much for all your support!
Huh?
And then, yeah.
Director, Gene?
The actor's work may be all done,
but for our boy Gene here,
it's only just beginning.
Huh?
Oh, right!
It still needs to be edited.
Editing is the most vital part of the film.
Everything's riding on Gene now.
He's editing his own movie?
That's not typical for a director.
I always have my directors do it themselves if they can, but...
But what?
You see, this film has the makings of a masterpiece.
However, the editor is the first test audience.
Directing is subjective, but editing is objective.
So now, does our Gene have what it takes to bridge that gap and find the perfect cut, I wonder?
Is it true?
The characters...
Time to edit.
This is gonna be so much fun.
I must be the happiest person on the face of the earth right now.
We shot about 72 hours of film,
but now,
what do I do with it?
I'm making a movie starring Martin Braddock.
It needs to be impressive.
I need a lot of depth right at the start.
Lots of fanfare.
I'm not going to show the whole concert.
I'll jump cut to the next scene before the audience gets bored.
Evening, dollbear.
Masterful performance, my friend.
Scene 12.
Interior, the concert hall's green room.
We shot eight different camera angles.
I'll line them up chronologically.
Evening, dollbear.
Masterful performance, my friend.
Don't patronize me.
I'm going to need you to find me a better Flavidus Coleman.
Let me ask you.
You have any idea what she costs?
And let me ask you.
Who am I to you?
The great dollbear.
That said, if your next concert is a success,
you'll become an international legend.
This I promise you.
I'm doing St. Matthew Passion.
Huh? Are you sure?
Do you have a problem with that?
Well, with you conducting it, I'm sure it'll be perfect.
Technically speaking, at least.
But a passion requires, well, you know, actual passion.
Which I can't provide.
I ask you again.
Who am I to you?
There's nothing but exposition in this scene.
Let's try this.
Don't patronize me.
I'm going to need you to find me a better Flavidus Coleman.
Let me ask you.
You have any idea what she costs?
And let me ask you.
Who am I to you?
I'll start with the wide shots.
That'll create a sense of mystery surrounding Delbert.
And by emphasizing Martin's emotionless delivery,
it'll increase the tension of the scene.
Ordinarily, one would transition to a medium shot here.
But I'm going to rattle the audience by jumping straight to the close-up.
I ask you again.
Who am I to you?
That's it.
This shows off Dalbert's prickly personality.
I'll keep employing this tactic.
Scene 24, page 20 of the screenplay.
Delbert finally leaves for Switzerland.
But it's taken 90 minutes of story just to get here.
And what's worse,
we won't get to meet Lily for another 30 minutes at least.
How do I fix this?
What?
Pampo's in Australia right now?
Yes.
She's currently there scouting for locations with Director Corbett.
How long will she be gone?
For about another two weeks.
Oh, I see.
Uh, she did leave you a message.
She did?
I expect to see the final cut in my inbox as soon as I get back.
So don't let me down.
That was the whole message.
I don't have a choice.
I have to start over from the top.
Evening, Dalbert.
Masterful performance, my friend.
Do you even know how to read music?
Again, from the top.
I want the orchestra replaced.
Have you lost your mind, Dalbert?
The concert is in two weeks.
How am I supposed to find that many musicians that quickly?
Have you lost your mind, Dalbert?
Just answer me this.
What does this aria mean to you?
Evening, Dalbert, my friend.
I'm quick, Dalbert.
I'm sorry.
You brought this on yourself.
You've grown careless, dollbear.
You didn't even bother to lock your door.
You and I have history.
Naturally, I feel responsible for what's happened.
How many years has it been now since your wife and kid left?
Why are you bringing that up now?
Maybe it's time you took a break.
Get away.
Use it to do some self-reflection.
What am I without music?
Nothing.
It's Mr. Peterson.
Uh, excuse me, sir.
Wow.
Oh, aren't you the...
It's Jean.
I, uh, didn't mean to disturb you.
But what are you doing?
I'm just having fun with some old film.
Amazing.
That's an actual film splicer.
It's an old man's hobby.
Trying to create a story from discarded film by piecing them together.
Huh.
Uh.
Um, I was wondering...
All the scenes feel important, and they're all wonderful performances.
But I have to cut a ton or it'll be too long.
Tell me.
Why don't you ask Pompo?
Uh.
Well...
I get it.
Pompo is the screenwriter, isn't she?
What's the point of you editing the movie if you can only do what she tells you to?
Right.
Jean.
Huh?
Who do we make movies for?
Well, for the audience, I guess.
And Jean, what is it about movies that you love so much?
Uh.
I'm guessing you found yourself in them.
Does that sound right?
Through them, you experienced empathy, dreams, longing.
You experienced life.
Now, tell me, Jean.
Have you found yourself in your movie yet?
Hmm.
Once you have, you'll find your passion.
Put it in your film, like you would an Aria.
What's my Aria?
What?
You've never strolled through the mountains before?
And how will doing that enhance my music?
Uh.
Hmm.
An Aria is a musical solo used to express emotion.
Back home, they worshiped me.
I devoted everything I had to music.
But for who?
Uh.
Ah.
So ask yourself, what are you trying to express?
But also, to whom do you want to express it?
Do you even know how to read music?
Again, from the top.
What's wrong?
Do you think you're better than the score?
Is that why you're not following it?
No.
But if you want me to keep playing,
just answer me this.
What does this Aria mean to you?
Oh.
That's it.
I found it.
Hold on.
That song.
I'm not on that one.
I love it.
Hold on.
It's me. It's me.
Wait a minute. That means...
Do not fear, Port Pumple has returned!
I'm glad you're back.
Okay, Gene, I want to see the film.
Well, it isn't quite finished.
Huh?
It isn't quite finished.
Could you repeat that?
It isn't quite finished?
How long is it?
I started over from scratch,
and there's about 72 hours of footage left.
Well, explain.
Our very first screening is scheduled for two weeks from now,
and all of our sponsors will be there.
They're going to pull funding if it isn't ready.
So, you had better give me a damn good reason for this delay, Gene.
It's missing something!
A scene.
Are you telling me you want to do additional shooting?
Yes.
As I'm sure you're already aware,
additional shoots means reassembling the entire crew.
Now, Gene, do you have any idea how hard that is?
I can imagine.
You need a crew in order to make a movie,
but most of them have moved on to other projects by now,
which means calling in favors and rescheduling other shoots.
Who do you think pays for that, huh, Gene?
You do, miss.
And getting your cast to come back is an even bigger nightmare.
Who do you think negotiates that, huh, Gene?
You do, miss.
Lastly, who wrote the screenplay that you feel is missing a scene?
You did, miss.
Now I ask you again.
Are you telling me you want to do additional shooting?
Where is this coming from?
Because, quite frankly, I think it's insane.
You actually want to attempt that Arya again?
Don't there.
You're only embarrassing yourself.
I've never understood it.
No, I'd somehow forgotten it.
The smell of fish or the pain of slipping in the rain.
Even the breeding of goats.
What?
Stop.
Oceans, memories.
They're important.
And that young girl reminded me of that.
I know I can do the peace justice now.
Face it.
You're all washed up.
Why don't you just give up already?
Because in spite of everything.
This is all I have.
My art.
And so.
Please.
My music needs.
My movie needs.
Another shot at the Arya.
Another scene for the film.
I beg you.
Pombo?
Fine.
I'll see what I can do.
Huh?
Unbelievable.
I never dreamed that kid would challenge me.
Why does he have to be so stubborn?
And yet?
I've never seen you happier.
Oh, Alan.
What do you want?
Well, sir, I've just been thinking that this job...
Wait, what is this thing?
Hey, who said you could take that?
It's an investment proposal for a film.
I was just about to call them to say that we aren't interested.
Wait, you're passing?
They canceled their screening because the director couldn't finish the edit in time.
So all their sponsors pulled out.
Investing in movies is a very high-risk venture.
What if the director never manages to complete the film?
Sir, give it to me, and I'll manage the account.
Huh?
Well?
It's perfect.
I never thought I'd have to write an additional scene at your request.
I'm so sorry.
I just thought it'd be more consistent if you were the one to write it.
I guess all directors end up as arrogant and selfish as you're being.
But who are you going to cast in this brand new part?
We don't have time to hold any auditions.
Well, actually, I already have someone perfect in mind.
The Meister script?
Uh-huh.
Yeah, that's right.
It's a new draft because they added one more scene.
Huh.
But our sponsors pulled out, so without additional funding, we won't be able to shoot it.
Actors are powerless in these kinds of situations.
Huh?
You can't have a board out there.
Allow me to just take this.
You're amusing.
Uh, uh, Mistia?
Hello?
Uh, oh, sorry.
Here.
Hmm?
Uh, this is awful.
How on earth am I going to market this thing?
Hello, Petersen Film.
Alan Gardner from the Alleywood Bank?
Your bank didn't get back to us.
I assumed they rejected our proposal.
Well, technically the bank has.
However...
You sure?
Yes.
That's good.
You prepared to lose everything if you fail?
Yes.
Then welcome to a world of dreams and madness.
This could get you fired.
There's no success without risk.
Am I right?
Yeah, but still.
Send me what you have and I'll help.
Huh?
You won't be ready in time at this rate.
And so, I recommend that we invest in Meister.
Even with a big star like Martin attached, the director's new.
It also doesn't bode well that the film's gotten bad press, which makes it too risky in my book.
I vote we don't invest.
The meeting's adjourned, then.
I haven't finished my presentation yet!
Mm-hmm.
I've always been good at embodying my characters.
Some say it's a gift.
Huh?
Yes.
It's been my dream since I was a girl.
I must have watched thousands of movies with my grandpa as a little kid.
But you know what?
Not a single one of them has ever truly moved me.
So then, is that what you're trying to do with this movie?
Except I can't be the one to make it.
Because then I wouldn't be able to enjoy it.
See?
That's where Gene comes in.
It's why you hired him to direct it.
Because out of all the movies, this one is your dream.
So how long has this been your dream?
Well, uh...
I've always loved watching movies, ever since I was a kid.
I didn't have any friends, but I didn't really care.
I mean, there were so many movies to watch.
So many I hadn't seen yet.
But there was a girl.
In every theater I went to, she was there.
She never stayed, though.
She always left when the end credits began.
I can't even remember her face.
But I always wondered...
What was it that drew her to the movies?
And had she never been so engrossed in a film that she wanted to stay till the end?
Until after the credits had rolled?
When I think about it, it's the reason I wanted to make a movie myself.
Movies saved me.
So maybe...
Someone else will be saved by mine.
And then I finally saw it.
Myself in the movie.
This movie.
I made it for the me all those years ago.
No.
Not just for me.
I see.
It needed a character that everyone can identify with.
Someone who, no matter who watches it, can believe in.
It's what helped me realize that the movie was lacking a very important scene.
One little crucial scene it required that would make the movie complete.
To show what we sacrifice in order to be able to pursue our dreams.
And so I beg you.
Please, make my dreams come true.
You know, things always came naturally, and I succeeded at everything.
Or so I thought.
But, looking back at it, what have I actually accomplished?
What's the point of anything if it doesn't have meaning?
And once I came to that realization, I knew I had to find something for myself.
I ask you, what is a banker's job really, if not to give people the means to fulfill their dreams?
So, please, we want to make a movie that will give people who have nothing a way to keep on dreaming!
I'll admit I agree with what you said.
That is exactly what bankers ought to do.
But we can't make decisions based on philosophy.
You need to convince us with concrete figures, not just nice stories.
Figures.
I have those figures.
You do?
What's this?
You've been filming us?
I do apologize.
But not only that, I've been streaming this entire meeting worldwide.
Hon.
What?
Our documentary is also available online.
What's more...
You're crowdfunding it?
We launched this website a few days ago.
This was how much we raised on the very first day.
And this is the fun now.
And the campaign is approaching two million views.
So, how do you like those figures?
Now, that's the conclusion of my presentation.
Cut the stream.
I'm afraid your little stunt has failed.
As such, you are to clear out your desk immediately.
There's no profit in dreams.
But why all the long faces?
You put on quite an entertaining show.
You should be proud.
Mr. President!
Hurry!
Turn off the stream!
A certain someone informed me of this, and I'm glad they did.
I was watching.
You know, it's by far the best presentation I've seen in a long time.
And it took resolve and great courage in order to pull it off.
This little project has a lot of potential.
We'll invest ten times the crowdfunding amount.
How's that sound?
But, sir...
You're using past indices as indicators of potential growth.
But you're ignoring a very important element.
What do you mean?
Take a look at this.
Notice a spike in the funding.
Any of you want to guess what happened at that moment to motivate that spike?
It's the moment when Gene Feeney and Alan Gardner were pouring their hearts out to us.
Assessing potential means looking towards the future.
By investing in their dreams, they're investing in their future.
Even so...
And the Ollywood Bank invests in people who will invest in their dreams.
That is our motto.
Hold on. Since when is that our motto?
Since now.
What?
And Alan, you've got a very bright future ahead of you.
Oh, yes!
Nicely done.
Thank you so much, sir.
Oh, man.
I can't remember the last time we've had such a crazy meeting.
It reminds me of back when the president was still a junior executive.
We'll invest!
Oh, that was thrilling!
I really appreciate you all for coming back to shoot this additional scene.
Everyone wins it for the world!
Why are you standing around?
Everyone's here because we've got a crucial scene to shoot, right?
Oh, everyone.
Thank you so much.
The scene we'll be shooting is a flashback to when Dalbert loses his family.
So, who's playing my wife?
Who's playing my wife?
That would be me.
Wow.
I'm Martin Braddock and the best actor in the world.
Want to add me to your socials?
Sorry, but I don't have a smartphone.
Hmm?
Wait a sec, have we met before?
I don't see how that could be.
Amazing.
I would never know that was Mystia.
Well, you better not.
All thanks to Nyallywood's tough prosthetic makeup artist.
By the way, don't tell anyone that it's her.
Also, she wants to use a pseudonym in the credits.
Why?
Is she embarrassed by the role?
It's not that.
I'll do it under one condition.
No one must know that it's me, okay?
Do you not like the part or something?
Oh, no.
It's not that.
And it's not that I don't want to make a movie with Jean and Natalie.
Because I do.
And I'm sure I will one day.
But...
When that time comes, I want to play the lead.
And until then, I don't want to appear in any of Jean's movies.
You've got a deal.
I'll make it work.
Hair and makeup will make you completely unrecognizable.
Great.
Miss Pompo?
Well, hurry up and get to work!
And action!
And so, thanks to Pompo's amazing skill as a producer,
not to mention the crew's efforts,
we managed to finish the movie.
Excuse me, Director Jean?
Oh, Missy!
Hey there, Natalie.
Mistia said you were busy editing, so I brought you food.
I'm just gonna leave it.
Whoa, what happened?
You look like a panda!
Oh, right.
I haven't slept much.
How much sleep do you have to miss to get bags like that?
I can't really say.
The last few days have been a blur.
What?
You'll end up killing yourself!
Thanks to the bank's generosity, we can afford to finish the movie.
Oh, you still need to show it to them in about a week.
I see.
Well, how much of it do you still have left to cut?
Uh, about three hours, I think.
That much?
Will you be able to finish the time?
Uh, I mean, I have a whole week, so probably...
What?
Ah!
Miss Popo!
How's our Jean doing?
He's sleeping.
Oh, no.
He's fine.
They think it's just anemia and say he should recover after some rest.
That means...
Yep.
From overwork.
One more thing.
The doctor insists that he's going to need to stay in bed till the end of the week.
If that's the case...
With Jean out of commission, I'll need to find someone else to finish editing.
You look so peaceful when you're sleeping.
I really wanted to see your movie.
Your edit.
I was looking forward to it.
Jean, can I come in?
Huh?
What?
I thought you'd be here.
Let's go back to the hospital.
I can't.
But you have to.
If someone else edits this, then it won't be my movie anymore.
Huh?
When I was doing the additional shooting, I remembered something.
How old is Lila now?
I'm not going to let you see her after this.
Come on.
You're being unreasonable.
Make your choice.
Stop trying to stall.
Do you choose us or your music?
I'll take your silence as your answer.
What?
So I'm just supposed to quit music?
We were always invisible to you.
But we're not going to be.
Not anymore.
The last thing I'll say is this.
Your music truly is wonderful.
However...
That Arya...
Everyone is right.
It's awful.
In order to create something great...
You have to sacrifice everything.
Not just your own life.
But everyone's.
And their money, too.
That's why...
I refuse to give up.
Hmm...
Hmm?
In that case...
I'm not leaving either.
Huh?
Because...
It's my movie, too, you know?
Huh?
Unbelievable.
You two are something else.
Hmm.
Uh...
That's the first scene I shot.
Yeah, sorry.
But it's not necessary, so I'm going to have to cut it.
Ah!
My first scene I shot with Martin!
Ah...
Ah!
It's okay.
Because I... I trust you.
What's life but a series of choices?
Choosing one path means cutting out all others.
And so, you cut out conversations.
Cut out friendships.
Cut out... the family.
Cut out everyday responsibilities.
Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut!
Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. criss roots.
Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Cut. Man.
In order to succeed, in order to keep what's left over, in order to not give up, I will cut!
Because this... is my... ARIA!
Does this mean you finished it?
Maybe... I don't even know.
Huh? How long?
How does one know when it's done?
Oh wait! How long is it?
How long?
How long is it? How long is it?
How long is it?
This is... this is your ARIA.
Gotta hand it to your doll bear. You did it.
You devoted your entire life to music, didn't you?
Is that conductor smiling?
You found it. Your ARIA.
Mother?
They say dreams and memories lay dormant in music, and you've invoked them all into this symphony of sound.
I know what you gave up in exchange. But gone are the bad times, the mistakes, the loneliness. This is our ARIA.
Huh?
It's weird.
The music... is bringing back some old memories.
Umm...
Ahhhh!
Aaaaaah!
I love you
Ms. Pompo, would you...
You're a real director.
Huh.
Your film.
It moved me.
Sure enough, just as Pompo predicted, the movie was a massive hit.
Uh, hello?
Yes. Yes. Well, I hope you give it some thought.
No problem. I'm actually headed there right now.
And then...
Meister has nabbed three awards tonight,
but will it win the remaining Best Director and Best Picture as well?
The Anteater gets hit by Gamma Rays, grows huge,
and wicks her all over, like bleh bleh bleh bleh.
You have to let me direct it!
And the Academy Award for Best Director goes to...
Jean B.
And the Academy Award for Best Director goes to Meister!
So tell us,
if you had to pick one favorite thing about the film,
what would it be?
Uh, pick one favorite thing?
That's it?
Uh...
My favorite thing about the movie...
It's got to be that...
It's exactly 90 minutes long.
Well, if you want to Amazon,
well-known like,
I'm either husband,
I think it was for you to wear a kind
chart-of-sale
iPhone
By bringing it in
anime,
has a close heart
I hate that
no suchacity you have to do
anything but to know I don't see if it's okay.
Кап Exc000ers
earach
Very tough
It's spot Kamehwer
I'll see you next time.